The word "data" is defined as distinct pieces of information.
تُعرّف كلمة "البيانات" بأنها معلومات مميزة.
You may think of data as simply numbers on a spreadsheet,
ربما تفكرون في البيانات باعتبارها أرقام بسيطة في جدول بيانات،
but data can come in many forms.
لكن البيانات يمكن أن تأتي بأشكال عديدة.
From text to video to spreadsheets and databases to images to audio,
بداية من النصوص وحتى مقاطع الفيديو وجداول البيانات وقواعد البيانات والصور والمقاطع الصوتية،
and I'm sure I'm forgetting many other forms.
وأنا واثق أنني نسيت العديد من الأشكال الأخرى.
Utilizing data is the new way of the world.
استخدام البيانات هي الطريقة الجديدة التي يسير بها هذا العالم.
Data is used to understand and improve nearly every facet of our lives.
تُستخدم البيانات لفهم كل جانب من جوانب حياتنا تقريبًا وتحسينه.
From early disease detection to social networks
بداية من الاكتشاف المبكر للأمراض وحتى شبكات التواصل الاجتماعي
that allow us to connect and communicate with people around the world.
التي تمكننا من الاتصال والتواصل مع الناس في جميع أنحاء العالم.
No matter what field you're in,
بغض النظر عن مجالكم،
from insurance and banking, to medicine,
بداية من التأمين والبنوك وحتى الطب
to education, to agriculture,,
والتعليم والزراعة
to automotive, to manufacturing, and so on.
والسيارات والتصنيع، إلى آخره.
You can utilize data to make better decisions and accomplish your goals.
يمكنكم استخدام البيانات لاتخاذ قرارات أفضل وتحقيق أهدافكم.
We will be getting you started on the right foot to using your data in this course.
سنساعدكم في هذه الدورة التدريبية لكي تضعوا قدمكم على بداية الطريق الصحيح نحو استخدام بياناتكم.